# **Dwight Smith**

New York, NY (216) 835-0847 <u>dwightsmth@gmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/elismth | zeroOrder.com

## **Summary**

Software engineer with 5 years of experience building scalable, enterprise web applications used by millions of customers worldwide. With a focus on the design and implementation of large scale systems built with modern technologies including TypeScript, React and ASP.Net Core. Enthusiastic team player who works collaboratively across geographically distributed teams to deliver quality software in an agile environment.

## **Experience**

Gogotech, New York, NY - Software Engineer

August 2017 - October 2022

- Launched core features for high traffic website using React.js, TypeScript and other technologies while providing code reviews, QA testing and deployment support across transnational teams
- Performed critical front-end optimizations for proprietary single-page application through bug fixes and refactorings in addition to employed best practices such as file compression, CDN usage and caching
- Built backend RESTful API services with C# and .Net Core, utilizing various design patterns and techniques
- Developed automated testing suite for our client-side application using the Selenium framework, ultimately improving team productivity through the reduction of newly reported bugs in production

#### Focus Camera, Brooklyn, NY - Ecommerce Manager

January 2014 - August 2017

- Produced and managed online content for various e-commerce platforms by providing HTML and CSS support
- Collaborated closely with software developers and designers to curate and deliver quality experiences for end-users
- Analyzed sales data and related metrics to assist in the development of marketing campaign strategies

### G2G Consulting, Washington D.C. - Government Affairs Mediator

July 2012 - October 2013

- Authored governmental policy research for senior legislative personnel and published reports on analytical insights
- Coordinated meetings with congressional officials and contributed valuable dialog on behalf of several public entities
- Provided client management services in addition to technical support and other office related duties

## **Skills**

JavaScript | TypeScript | React.js | Node.js | C# | .Net Core | OOP | REST API | SQL | NoSQL | BDD | Python | Git | CI/CD

## **Education**

Cleveland State University, Cleveland, OH - Bachelor's of Science, Environmental Studies